Guide to the Luis Leal Papers, 1946-1985
Department of Special Collections
- Series 3: Manuscripts of articles, lectures, presentations
  - Subseries F: Luis Leal published articles, lectures, etc. (numbers refer to listings in Luis Leal, A Bibliography with Interpretative and Critical Essays. Eds. Salvador Güereña and Raquel Quiroz González. Berkeley: Chicano Studies Library Publications Unit, University of California at Berkeley, 
    - VIII. Published lectures: #335 - "Agustín Yáñez y la novela mexicana." San Diego State University, San Diego, Calif. 1 May 1981. (See 116). #339 - "The american in mexican literature." Pacific Coast Council on Latin American Studies. San Jose, Calif. 21 Oct. 1977. (See No. 119). #351 - "El Cautiverio feliz y la crónica novelesca." Ohio State University, Columbus. 17 April 1978. (See 44). #352 - "El Cautiverio feliz y la crónica novelesca." Seminar: "La prosa hispanoamericana del siglo XVII", MLA, New York. 27 Dec. 1974. (See 44). #365 - "Criollistas y peninsulares." LASA, New York. 8 Nov. 1968. #386 - "El ejemplo, género literario popular." Sociedad Folklórica de México, México. 10 March 1954. (read in absentia) (See No. 156). #388 - "Elementos novelescos en Ulises criollo." Panelist on symposium "José Vasconcelos en su centenario", MLA, Los Angeles, Calif. 28 Dec. 1982. (See No. 276). #396 - "The Future of Foreign Language Studies." Mississippi MLA, Jackson, Mississippi, 20 March 1953. #397 - "Gabino Barreda y la literatura: de la Preparatoria al Ateneo." UCLA, 14 May 1981. (See No. 168). #398 - "El gallo de oro, nueva novela de Juan Rulfo." University of Colorado, Boulder. 5 Dec. 1980. Homage to Juan Rulfo. (See No. 169). #399 - "El gallo de oro, un nuevo libro de Juan Rulfo." Cal State University, Dominguez Hills, Calif. 10 April 1980. #400 - "El gallo de oro y otros textos de Juan Rulfo." Barnard College, New York, 2 April 1982. Homage to Juan Rulfo. (See No. 170). #426 a - "The Mexican 'Soldadera' in Fact and Fiction: An Illustrated Lecture." California Lutheran College, Thousand Oaks, Calif. 3 May 1985. #427 - "The Mexican Soldaderas." Mills College, Oakland, Calif. 1 May 1984. Slide Lecture. #465 - "The Pursued hero in contemporary spanish-american fiction." A conference on twentieth century literature, University of Louisville, Kentucky. 10 March 1973. (See Nos. 174, 226). #472 - "Recuerdos de Ciudad Juárez en escritores de la Revolución." Primera feria del libro y festival de la cultura, Ciudad Juárez, México. 22 Aug. 1963. (see nos. 1, 21 & 232). #486 - "The soldadera in the literature of the mexican Revolution." Loyola Marymount University, Westchester, Calif. 5 May 1980. Illustrated Slide Lecture. #502 - "Las vueltas del tiempo, continuidad y cambio en los personajes de Agustín Yáñez." Pacific Coast Council on Latin American Studies, California State University, Chico. 19 Oct. 1979. (See No. 258 & 277). #503 - "Yáñez y la novela mexicana." International Symposium on Agustín Yáñez, UCLA Latin American Center. 25 Oct. 1980. (See No. 116). (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Subseries G: Luis Leal published manuscripts. (not included in Luis Leal, A Bibliography with Interpretative and Critical Essays. Eds. Salvador Güereña and Raquel Quiroz González. Berkeley: Chicano Studies Library Publications Unit, University of California at Berkeley, 1988)
    - Las publicaciones de la Universidad Nacional de México. Foreign languages in the elementary schools. Cuento hispanoamericano / Cuento mexicano; conversaciones de Luis Leal y Seymour Menton. Guzmán, Martín Luis. La sombra del caudillo; versión priodística. Estudio introductorio [de] Bruce-Novoa. Ilustraciones de Jesús Gómez Linares y Liliana Mercenario Pomeroy. (Book Review). Los de abajo: Lectura temática. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Cuentistas mexicanos contemporáneos. Juan Rulfo. (16 May 1918--7 January 1986). José Rubén Romero. Mariano Azuela. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - (Folder of unclassified, unidentified parts of manuscripts by Luis Leal). (Box 33, Folder 5)
- Series 4: Dissertations
  - Subseries A: Dissertations (unpublished ) directed by Luis Leal (titles taken from pp. 80-83 of Luis Leal, A Bibliography with Interpretative and Critical Essays. University of California at Berkeley, 1988)
    - #504 - Aldeman, Constance. "La obra literaria del Dr. Atl." 1976. pp. 1-136. (cont...) (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - #504 - Aldeman, Constance. "La obra literaria del Dr. Atl." 1976. pp. 137-269. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - #509 - Bevelanders, Charles Donald. "Point of view, Mario Vargas Llosa's conversación en la catedral." 1975. (cont...) (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - #509 - Bevelanders, Charles Donald. "Point of view, Mario Vargas Llosa's conversación en la catedral." 1975. (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - #510 - Birkemoe, Diane Solomon. "Contemporary women novelists of Argentina (1945-1967. 1968. pp. 1-169 (cont...) (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - #510 - Birkemoe, Diane Solomon. "Contemporary women novelists of Argentina (1945-1967. 1968. pp. 170-336 (cont...) (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - #511 - Blackburn, Carol P. Roark. "The picaresque novel in Mexico." 1969. pp. 1-146 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - #512 - Brann, Sylvia Jean. "El teatro y las novelas de Luisa Josefina Hernández." 1969. pp. 1-151 (cont...) (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - #512 - Brann, Sylvia Jean. "El teatro y las novelas de Luisa Josefina Hernández." 1969. pp. 152-310 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - #519 - Cowes, María del Rosario Ferrer de. "Literatura y política en la obra de David Viñas." 1976. pp. 1-107 (cont...) (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - #519 - Cowes, María del Rosario Ferrer de. "Literatura y política en la obra de David Viñas." 1976. pp. 108-262 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - #520 - Cruz, María Carmen. "La forma diario en la narrativa hispanoamericana contemporánea." 1974. pp. 1-99 (cont...) (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - #520 - Cruz, María Carmen. "La forma diario en la narrativa hispanoamericana contemporánea." 1974. pp. 100-233 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - #522 - D'Lugo, Marvin Alan. "Self-conscious' form: The perception of reality in contemporary latin american fiction." 1970. pp. 1-237 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - #525 - Francescato, Martha Paley de. "El bestiario de Julio Cortázar: enriquecimiento de un género." pp. 1-159. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - #528 - Guice, Norma W. "La narrativa social de Augusto Céspedes." 1973. pp. 1-149. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - #529 - Hernández, David. "Alfonso Reyes as a literary critic." 1966. pp. 1-89. (cont...) (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - #529 - Hernández, David. "Alfonso Reyes as a literary critic." 1966. pp. 90-204. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - #530 - Herz, Theda Mary. "Satire in Juan José Arreola's confabulario." 1972. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - #531 - Jeffrey, Iris Catherine. "The narrative art of Rafael Felipe Muñoz." 1969. Published: El arte narrativo de Rafael Felipe Muñoz. Madrid: Ediciones José Porrua Turanzas, 1986. 161 pp. (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - #532 - Jiménez-Sánchez, Reynaldo Luis. "Guillermo Cabrera Infante y tres tristes tigres." 1974. Published: Guillermo Cabrera Infante y "tres tristes tigres." Miami: Ediciones Universal, 1977. pp. 1-89 (cont...) (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - #532 - Jiménez-Sánchez, Reynaldo Luis. "Guillermo Cabrera Infante y tres tristes tigres." 1974. Published: Guillermo Cabrera Infante y "tres tristes tigres." Miami: Ediciones Universal, 1977. pp. 90-186 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - #534 - Nigro, Kristen Felicia. "José Donoso and the grotesque." 1973. pp. 1-129 (cont...) (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - (con t...) #534 - Nigro, Kristen Felicia. "José Donoso and the grotesque." 1973. pp. 130-259 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - #535 - Orrantia, Dagoberto. "La situación del narrador como principio formal en cuatro obras representativas de la nueva novela hispanoamericana." 1976. (cont...) (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - #535 - Orrantia, Dagoberto. "La situación del narrador como principio formal en cuatro obras representativas de la nueva novela hispanoamericana." 1976. (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - #536 - Parent, Anamaría Ferrán. "El narrador niño: un punto de vista limitado." 1976. (cont...) (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - #536 - Parent, Anamaría Ferrán. "El narrador niño: un punto de vista limitado." 1976. (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - #541 - Snook, Margaret Louise. "Theme and narrative technique in representative fantastic works of Adolfo Bioy Casares." 1975. pp. 1-165 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - #543 - Tanner, Roy Lynn. "Characterization in the tradiciones peruanas of Ricardo Palma." 1976. pp. 1-159 (cont...) (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - #543 - Tanner, Roy Lynn. "Characterization in the tradiciones peruanas of Ricardo Palma." 1976. pp. 160-325 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - #544 - Valdés, Bernardo José. "El cuento cubano en la República (1902-1959)." 1973. pp. 1-144 (cont...) (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - #544 - Valdés, Bernardo José. "El cuento cubano en la República (1902-1959)." 1973. pp. 145-264 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - #545 - Valdéz, Richard Albert. "The aesthetic use of philosophical theories in the prose works of Jorge Luis Borges." 1975. pp. 1-139 (cont...) (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - #545 - Valdéz, Richard Albert. "The aesthetic use of philosophical theories in the prose works of Jorge Luis Borges." 1975. pp. 140-289 (cont...) (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - #545 - Valdéz, Richard Albert. "The aesthetic use of philosophical theories in the prose works of Jorge Luis Borges." 1975. pp. 290-428 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - #547 - Young, Rina Rebecca Stowell. "Six representative women novelists of Mexico." 1975. pp. 1-99 (cont...) (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - #547 - Young, Rina Rebecca Stowell. "Six representative women novelists of Mexico." 1975. pp. 100-233 (cont...) (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Subseries B: Dissertations (unpublished ) directed by others, (not Luis Leal).
    - Malcolm Scott Mackenzie. "Emilio Carballido" an ideational evaluation of his theatre." pp. 1-114 (cont...) (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Malcolm Scott Mackenzie. "Emilio Carballido" an ideational evaluation of his theatre." pp. 115-239 (cont...) (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Malcolm Scott Mackenzie. "Emilio Carballido" an ideational evaluation of his theatre." pp. 240-350 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Eliud Martínez. Mariano Azuela and "The height of the times": European modernism in La malhora, El desquite and La luciérnaga. pp. 1-123 (cont...) (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Eliud Martínez. Mariano Azuela and "The height of the times": European modernism in La malhora, El desquite and La luciérnaga. pp. 1-104 (cont...) (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Eliud Martínez. Mariano Azuela and "The height of the times": European modernism in La malhora, El desquite and La luciérnaga. pp. 106-194 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Francisco Lomelí. "Carlos Drogett: Poética de la obsesión y el martirio." pp. 1-89 (cont...) (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Francisco Lomelí. "Carlos Drogett: Poética de la obsesión y el martirio." pp. 90-199 (cont...) (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Francisco Lomelí. "Carlos Drogett: Poética de la obsesión y el martirio." pp. 200-302 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - J. Rolando Romero-Durán: El concepto de escritura en hispanoamerica: El caso de Salvador Elizondo. (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Stephen James Summerhill: The idea of literature in Miguel de Unamuno. (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - William Impens: A lexicon of aboriginal terms as found in the indigenist novel of the andean region. (cont...) (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - William Impens: A lexicon of aboriginal terms as found in the indigenist novel of the andean region. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Mary Lois Jones: Francisco Monterde's works of fiction (M.A. Thesis). (cont...) (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Mary Lois Jones: Francisco Monterde's works of fiction (M.A. Thesis). (carbon copy) (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Kira Inés Pablete Araya: Trayectoria del surrealismo en las revistas literarias argentinas. (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Olena Hykawyk Saciuk: A comparative study of the cowboy, gaucho, and kozak as protagonists in selected novels. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Subseries C: Graduate student committees in which Luis Leal served at the University of Illinois
    - Committees on which Luis Leal served for doctoral candidates. (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Committees on which Luis Leal served for doctoral candidates. (cont...) (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Subseries D
    - Curricula vitae of academic persons. cont... (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - cont... Curricula vitae of academic persons. (Box 42, Folder 4)
- Series 5: Diccionarios
  - Subseries A: Diccionario de Aztequismos by Luis Leal
    - Aztequismos I. (vocabulario entries). (unpublished ) A-C (Box 43)
    - Aztequismos II. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) CH-J (Box 44)
    - Aztequismos III. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) M-S (Box 45)
    - Aztequismos IV. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) T (Box 46)
    - Aztequismos V. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) U-Z (Box 47)
  - Subseries B: Diccionario de Mexicanismos by Luis Leal
    - Mexicanismos I. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) A (Box 48)
    - Mexicanismos II. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) B-Carey (Box 49)
    - Mexicanismos III. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) Carga-Cazquear (Box 50)
    - Mexicanismos IV. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) CH-E (Box 51)
    - Mexicanismos V. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) F-K (Box 52)
    - Mexicanismos VI. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) L-0 (Box 53)
    - Mexicanismos VII. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) P-Pochiche (Box 54)
    - Mexicanismos VIII. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) Pochismo-Tercerola (Box 55)
    - Mexicanismos IX. (vocabulary entries). (unpublished) Terciar armas-Z (Box 56)
  - Subseries C: Supplementary entries for Diccionario de Aztequismos and Diccionario de Mexicanismos by Luis Leal
    - Supplemet I. A-Chia (Box 57)
    - Supplement II. Chiantic-T (Box 58)
    - Supplement III. Texochilli Also, miscellaneous notes on Nahuatl; notes on El español en México. (Box 59)
  - Subseries D: Abbreviations for Diccionario de Aztequismos and Diccionario de Mexicanismos. Also, entries on botanical names of plants found in Mexico
    - El español en México. Abbreviations for bibliographical sources used for the dictionaries of Aztequismos and Mexicanismos. Standley, Paul C. Trees and shrubs of Mexico. Up to p. 376 Names of plants used in Mexico with scientific botanical name. (Box 60)
  - Subseries E: 1. Original hand-written cards for Diccion ario de Aztequismos and Diccionario de Mexicanismos by Luis Leal. 2. Miscellaneous hand-written cards for Diccionario de Aztequismos by Luis Leal.
    - IV. Sirigonza-Zurumato. (Box 64)
    - I. C-G (Box 61)
    - II. H-Palo de asta (Box 62)
    - III. Palo de barranco-Siquete (Box 63)
  - Subseries:
- Series 6: Reference Materials
  - Subseries A: Luis Leal research folders on Mexico: General, literature, culture, history - (not authors) A-Z
    - Academia de la Lengua. (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Ajusco. (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - El americano in mexican literature. (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Arquitectura. (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Arte mexicano - Colonial. (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Arte mexicano - 19th Century. (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Arte mexicano - Contemporáneo. (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Artes populares. (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Asociación de escritores de México. (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Aztecas. (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Baile. (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Baja California. (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Bestiarios. (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Bibliografías - México (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Book reviews. From hispano americano (tiempo) (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Caricatura. (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Cinema. (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Ciudad Juárez. (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Crítica literaria - Notas. (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Cronistas. (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Cronologías. (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Cucaracha. (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Día de la Raza. (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Economía. (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Ejemplo. (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Ensayos. (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Estridentismo. (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Filosofía y religión. (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Folklore. (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Fronteras. (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Generación del centenario. (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Guadalajara. (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - José María Heredia. (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Historia mexicana (revista). (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - History (see mexican revolution). (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Humorismo. (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Indigenismo. (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Italian literature in Mexico. (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Jicotencatl. (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Benito Juárez. (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Frida Kahlo (see Rivera, Diego). (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Oscar Lewis. (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Leyendas y mitos. (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Literatura mexicana (general). (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Literatura mexicana - Teoría. (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Literatura popular mexicana. (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Lorenzo, Agustín. (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Mayas. (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Mexican revolution. (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Mexicanismos. (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - México (general; miscellaneous on Mexico). (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Mexico City. (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Mexico's cities. (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Mexico and the United States. (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Mujer - Arquetipos femeninos. (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Mujer - Muerte. (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Música. (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Nacionalidad. (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Orozco, Clemente. (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Orquestra, La. (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Otomí. (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Pavo, El. (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Periodismo. (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Edgar Allen Poe in Mexico. (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Poesía. (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Político. (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Posada, José G. (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Proverbios. (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Ramos Martínez, Alfredo. (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Revistas y periódicos. (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Rivero, Diego. (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Ruelas, Julio. (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Sarape. (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Soldadera. (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Seudónimos. (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Sinestesia. (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Siqueros, David Alfaro. (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Teatro. (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Theses & Dissertations about Mexico. (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Tlatelolco. (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Totonacos. (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Unamuno - Mexico in the imagination of Unamuno. (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Utopia. (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Vanguardismo. (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Pancho Villa. (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Virgen de Guadalupe. (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Volador. (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Zapata, Emilio. (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Zapotecas (Oaxaca). (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Zaragoza. (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Zorrilla en México. (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Subseries B: Luis Leal research folder files on latin america. General, literature, culture. A-Z
    - Alegría, Ciro. (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Alegría, Fernando. (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Anglo American Literature in Latin America. (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Arévalo Martínez, Rafael. (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Argentina. (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Asturias, M. A. (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Asturias - Mulata de tal. (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Barrios, Eduardo. (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Bello, Andrés. (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Benedetti, Marío. (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Bibliografía (L.A.) (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Bioy-Casares, Adolfo. (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Bolivia. (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Bombal, María Luisa. (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Borges, J. L. (cont...) (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Borges, J. L. (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Borges - Ensayos (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Brazil. (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Cabrera Infante, Guillermo> (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Carpentier, Alejo.> (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Carvalho-Neto, P. (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Casal, Julián del. (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Central America. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Chile. (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Colón, Cristóbal. (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Colombia. (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Concolorcorvo. (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Cortázar, Julio. (cont...) (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Cortázar, Julio. (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Cortázar, Julio - Cuento. (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Costa Rica. (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Crítica literaria (L.A.) (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Cuba. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Cuento - Contemporáneo. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Cuento - Modernista. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Cuento - Teoría. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Cultura - Latin America. (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Darío, Rubén. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Dominican Republic. (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Echeverría, Esteban. (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Ecuador. (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - El Salvador. (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Ercilla, Alonso de. (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Fernando de Oviedo. (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Gallegos, Rómulo. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Gálvez, Manuel. (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - García Márquez, Gabriel. (cont...) (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - García Márquez, Gabriel. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - García Márquez en México. (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Gaucho. (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Guatemala. (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Che Guevara. (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Güiraldes, Ricardo. (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Haití. (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Honduras. (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - General John Hawkins in spanish america. (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Hernández, Filisberto. (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Hernández, José. (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Historiografía de la literatura hispanoamericana. (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Hostos, E. M. de. (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Huidobro, Vicente. (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Icaza, Jorge. (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Instituto Internacional de Literatura Iberoamericana. (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Isaacs, Jorge. (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Labrador, Ruiz. (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Lezama Lima, José. (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Literatura Colonial. (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Lugones, Leopoldo. (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Mallea, Eduardo. (cont...) (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Mallea, Eduardo. (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Mariátegui, José Carlos. (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Marqués, René. (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Mistral, Gabriela. (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Martí, José. (cont...) (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Martí, José. (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Martínez Estrada, Ezequiel. (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Mead, Robert G. (Box 7 9, Folder 7)
    - Mejía Sánchez, Ernesto. (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Menén Desleal, Alvaro. (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Modernismo. (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Montes Huidobro, M. (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Murena, H. A. (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Neruda, Pablo. (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - Nicaragua. (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - Novás Calvo, Lino. (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Novela hispanoamericana. (cont...) (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Novela hispanoamericana. (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Núñez de Pineda y Bascuñán. (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Olmedo, José Joaquín de. (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Onetti, Juan Carlos. (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Palma, Ricardo. (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Panamá. (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Paraguay. (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Pardo García, Germán. (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Paz y Salgado. (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Perú - Incas. (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Picaresca hispanoamericana. (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Pita Rodríguez, Félix. (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Poetry. (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Post Modernismo. (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Prado, Pedro. (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Puerto Rico. (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Quiroga, Horacio. (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Real maravilloso. (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Realismo. (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Realismo mágico. (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Rivera, José Eustacio (1888-1928). (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Roa Bastos, A. (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Rodó, José Enrique. (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Raggiano, Alfredo. (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Ruiz, Mario. (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Sábato, Ernesto. (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Sánchez, Florencio. (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Sarmiento, Domingo Faustino. (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Silva, José Asunción. (Box 82, Folder 3)